Steve Schrader

M: 0448 440 381 | E: <u>steve36lives@hotmail.com</u>
Ashfield WA 6054

SUMMARY STATEMENT:

After 20+ years working in the transport industry, I moved to re-invent myself in 2019 by returning to studies to pursue a life-long passion for computing.

Now four years of study later, I have the Diploma of Advanced Programming (and Certificate of Excellence award) + units in web-development to my name. I particularly enjoyed the coding aspect as well as problem-solving and creating/transferring data-models into working code.

Since finalizing formal studies, I have been adding to my skill-set by following online lessons and tutorials in React, TypeScript and NextJS.

I now seek to attain a foot-hold role within the IT world to apply skills learned.

I consider myself to be a well-rounded individual with wide-ranging interests and skills that would make me an asset to any company employing my services. I am able to interact with people at all levels, am team-focused and detail-oriented and have an easy-going and personable nature.

I have a strong focus on client needs, a result of time working in service-industry positions.

EDUCATION:

Diploma of Advanced Programming (North Metropolitan TAFE)	2023
+ Certificate of Excellence	
MongoDB – m001 & m103 Certification (online)	2022
Certificate IV – Web Development (North Metropolitan TAFE)	2022
Certificate IV – Computer Programming (North Metropolitan TAFE)	2020

KEY SKILLS & ABILITIES:

Programming Languages:

- Java, C#, PHP, Python
- SQL(MariaDB/SQL Server, MySQL), NoSQL(MongoDB)
- Laravel/Postman
- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript/TypeScript
- ReactJS, Dart/Flutter

Skill-set:

- OOP (Object-Oriented Programming paradigm)
- Data-modelling (PowerBI, pandas)
- Creative problem analysis & resolution
- Clear and concise verbal and written communication skills
- Documentation (including specifications), user manuals, and code comments
- Friendly and informative customer service skills

LIVEWORKS PROJECTS AND LINKS:

Greenhouse Nursery Management App:

Our team developed an app to allow Horticulture students at Joondalup TAFE to input data on seedlings and plant growth over the duration of their course.

My responsibilities:

Collaborated with the client to understand their requirements

Worked as part of the project team to plan initial app design

Researched and gathered appropriate data to inform the process

Worked on UI elements using the Flutter programming language to develop app

Effectively communicated progress, challenges, and solutions with team members and client Implemented change based on client feedback

Assisted in the compiling of technical documentation and code documentation

PLUMS Project:

Initially part of the team to develop a web-site where potential TAFE students could take online quizzes to determine their prior knowledge level and assist with selecting an appropriate course of study.

My responsibilities:

Collaborated with the client to understand project requirements

Developed Laravel database project using PHP programming language to handle data interactions for the project

Conducted extensive testing of above using Postman

Created code documentation in order that future developers could extend the project

CaptainSteve:

The CaptainSteve website was created as part of my studies in web-based development. This has been included to showcase extra-curricular studies taken in JavaScript (a personal favourite). The website can be found at: www.captainsteveperth.com/.

Other examples of work undertaken can be found at my GitHub page. https://github.com/SteveSchrader65

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

<u>Fasta Couriers - Secure Document Destruction Driver - (Mar 2015 to Current)</u>

- Secure collection of confidential documentation
- Delivery of same to SUEZ recycling plant, Landsdale
- Liaise with a range of customers

Fasta Couriers – Fleet Controller – (June 2009 to Feb 2019)

- Despatch of ad hoc courier bookings to meet client requirements using Hub system
- Take telephone bookings & enter into Transpac booking system
- General office administration as required

John Holland Rail - Railway Maintenance Worker - (Sept 2005 to July 2006)

- Installation and removal of railway sleepers
- Operation of butt-weld plant and machinery
- Assembly of railway turn-outs

REFERENCES:

Cos Pacecca – General Manager, Fasta Couriers

E: cos@fastacouriers.com

M: 0401 838 711

Ben Hutton - Principal Software Engineer, Airscope Industries

E: ben@benhutton.com.au

M: 0434 211 939

Guido Verschoor – Head of Programming, TAFE North Metropolitan

E: guido.verschoor@nmtafe.wa.edu.au

Adrian Gould – Advanced Skills Lecturer, TAFE North Metropolitan

E: adrian.gould@nmtafe.wa.edu.au

Aaron Clifford – Software Development Lecturer, TAFE North Metropolitan

E: aaron.clifford@nmtafe.wa.edu.au

(Written references available upon request)